# Barsha Maharjan

# Frontend Web Designer & Developer

Barsha specializes in interactive UI Design and Development, crafting intuitive controls for website and software by combining elements of programming, psychology, and creative design. She is eager and quick to learn new technologies and implement them in products.

- 347-656-1805
- www.baarshaa.com
- im maharjanbarsha

## Experience

# Rapid Detection Systems

E-Commerce, NY Aug.2019 - Present

#### Frontend Web Developer

- Developed a custom responsive e-commerce website for premier security metal detectors using Shopify Liquid templating language
- Designed branding guideline, logo and graphics
- Managed maintenance of the website post-delivery

#### My Brain and Me

Medical Industry, NY Mar.2019 - Present

#### Frontend Web Designer and Developer

- · Redesigned brand, created logo, graphics and animated videos for marketing
- Created wireframes and interactable prototypes for easy user accessibility
- Developed the User Interface using Webpack, Html, Sass, JavaScript and handled cross-platform devices compatibility issues

#### Verizon 5G

Entrepreneurship, NY Jun.2018 - Aug.2018

#### **UX Researcher & Design Fellow**

- Built a new start-up in the sports arena in partnership with NYC Media Lab,
   Verizon, and Yahoo Sports
- Trained with NYC Media Lab through an 8-week Lean Launchpad program to encourage and support customer discovery and market validation

#### Feet in 2 Worlds

Journalism, NY Jul.2018 - Sep.2018

#### Web Designer

- Proposed and implemented new site content architecture and navigation scheme for company website redesign
- Developed logo, graphic images and effects to achieve design goals
- Developed interactable prototype concepts using Photoshop, invision app and concept designs

# Rapid Motion Services

E-Commerce, NY Jun.2018 - Sep.2018

#### Frontend Web Developer

- Designed and developed client's website from concept to final product
- Provided competitive market analysis on the e-commerce site and proposed suggestions to the design and available functionality
- Designed branding guideline, logo and graphics, hosting and web maintenance

# Himalayan Wild Fibers

Product Industry
Oct.2016 - Nov.2016

#### Web Designer and Developer

- Successfully created and developed new look and style for notable web presence
- Instrumental in branding, creative direction, art direction and design
- Developed web navigation improving usability and resulted in increased traffic

#### **Fusemachines**

Tech Industry, NY Mar.2014 - Jun.2017

#### **Frontend Web Developer**

- Created websites collaborating with front and back-end developers using standard HTML/CSS practices
- Worked directly with customers from law, technology and education industries to establish project scope, interaction guidelines, and project timelines
- Led the development of websites, built advanced UI frameworks for web applications, and established design patterns for rapid prototyping of website
- Designed web pages and applications that meet business and user goals through a positive user experience

# Education

# Master of Fine Arts, Design and Technology

Parsons School of Design, US

2017 - 2019

# **Bachelor of Computer Science, Information Management**

Saint Xavier's College, Nepal

2010 - 2014

## Skills

#### Web Design

wireframe, prototype, figma, invision app, sketch

#### Web Development

html, css, sass, javascript, gsap, tweenmax, gulp, webpack, github, bootstrap, shopify, squarespace

## Graphics Design

photoshop, illustrator

#### **Animation and Video**

after effects, premiere pro, blender, cinema 4d

### **Motion Capture**

motive, perception neuron

#### **Game Dev and Virtual Reality**

unity, htc vive, leap motion google cardboard,

### Awards

# We Are Here Film Festival

Official selection of short animated film, Chagu Bakha. 2019

### Dean's Merit Scholarship

Parsons School of Design. 2017